Pretty, sparkly, and really hard to get rid of.
漂亮、闪闪发光，而且很难去除。
Forms of glitter have been used for decoration since at least Aztec times and can be found on ornaments, clothes, greeting cards and cosmetics.
至少从阿兹特克时代起，各种形式的闪亮小物件就被用于装饰，可以在饰品、衣服、贺卡和化妆品上找到。
However, today's glitter is often made of plastic, and this makes it more dangerous than it appears.
然而，如今的闪亮饰物通常由塑料制成，这使它比看起来更危险。
Pieces of glitter are often washed into the water system, and from there into seas and rivers.
闪亮饰物碎片常被冲入排水系统，然后进入海洋和河流。
Here, they become microplastic pollution.
在那里，它们变成微塑料污染。
Fish often mistake small plastic particles for food and eat them.
鱼类常常将微小的塑料颗粒误认为食物并吃掉。
When something low in the food chain is eaten by predators, they also consume the microplastics left in their prey.
当食物链低端的生物被捕食者吃掉时，捕食者也会吞噬猎物体内的微塑料。
If we eat seafood, that includes us.
如果我们食用海鲜，我们也会摄入。
While there are still questions about the impact of this, microplastics have been linked with issues including DNA damage, organ dysfunction and cardiovascular problems.
虽然关于其影响仍有疑问，但微塑料已与DNA损伤、器官功能障碍和心血管问题等问题有关。
It's been estimated that humans may ingest between 74,000 and 121,000 microplastic particles each year.
据估计，人类每年可能摄入74,000到121,000个微塑料颗粒。
Glitter only makes up a tiny part of the microplastics found in the ocean, but it can be particularly harmful.
闪片只占海洋中微塑料的一小部分，但它可能特别有害。
Firstly, while most microplastics in marine environments are formed by large pieces of plastic breaking down, glitter is manufactured as a microplastic.
首先，虽然海洋环境中的大多数微塑料是由大块塑料分解形成的，但闪片是作为微塑料制造的。
It is also made up of several different compounds which can leach toxins into the surrounding environment.
它由几种不同的化合物组成，这些化合物可以将毒素浸出到周围环境中。
Additionally, a recent study has suggested that glitter particles can encourage the formation of certain mineral crystals, changing the chemistry of the environment around them.
此外，最近一项研究表明，闪片颗粒可以促进某些矿物晶体的形成，从而改变周围环境的化学性质。
Not only could this affect how sea life produces shells and skeletons, but the crystals can break up the particles further, forming nanoplastics.
这不仅会影响海洋生物产生外壳和骨骼的方式，而且晶体可以进一步分解颗粒，形成纳米塑料。
These are even more likely to be absorbed by marine organisms.
这些纳米塑料更有可能被海洋生物吸收。
Biodegradable alternatives have been developed, although some studies suggest that these could be just as harmful.
可生物降解的替代品已被开发出来，尽管一些研究表明这些替代品可能同样有害。
Maybe we should just find a different way to make decorations.
也许我们应该另寻他法来制作装饰品。